ordinarytraveler.com 2019-06-17

# Privacy Policy & Disclosure • Ordinary Traveler

## ordinarytraveler.com Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context.

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

### What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?

When subscribing to our email newsletter, you may be asked to enter your name and email address in order for us to send you weekly emails with travel tips and deals. Emails are strictly used for my newsletter only. The newsletter and email list have an opt-out link which can be used at any time to unsubscribe.

### How do we protect visitor information?

  * Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

  * We use regular Malware Scanning.

  * Our site is HTTPS secure.

### Do we use ‘cookies’?

  * Google Analytics uses cookies to gather information such as demographics, whether a visitor is using a mobile device or a desktop computer, whether a visitor is male or female. It does NOT collect your name, address, email, or phone number.

  * You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

  * If you disable cookies, some features may be disabled that make our site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

### Use of personal data

We do NOT require registration to use our site.

We do use 3rd party programs which do track  _some data_  including demographics and cookies that we want to outline below.

 _As mentioned above, virtually all websites use services like these- not just us!_

1.) We use Google Analytics to track the traffic and growth of our site and monitor site performance. Google Analytics tells us which countries and cities our visitors are located in, whether a visitor is using a mobile device or a desktop computer, whether a visitor is male or female. It does NOT collect your name, address, email, or phone number.

We only share broad demographic data when speaking to partners, and only personally use the data to provide a better user experience for you over time.

2.) We use a 3rd party advertising network (AdThrive) which delivers image-based ads to you in part based on our site’s content, your demographics (via #1 above), and your web usage (via cookies saved on your device).

We do not receive any data from our ad network regarding this, and we do not know what ads are explicitly delivered to you at any time.

3.) We use 3rd party social media networks and a mailing list service (MailChimp).

To use these features of our site you must explicitly opt-in by liking a social media profile or submitting your email address. Links and sign up forms for these are available on our site, but they are not required for use.

By opting in, we  _may_  have access to your name and email address.

We do not use personal data (name, email, mailing address, phone number) in any capacity beyond its intended use (i.e. delivering newsletters to subscribers).

### Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

### Third-party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by [Google’s Advertising Principles](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en). They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users.

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website. Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

### We have implemented the following:

Ads using a 3rd party advertising network (AdThrive)

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

### Opting out:

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy.

See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

### According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

  * Users can visit our site anonymously.

  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.

  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

  * Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page.

  * Users are able to change their personal information by emailing us.

### How does our site handle do not track signals?

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

### Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?

  * It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking.

  * When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

  * We do not specifically market to children under 13.

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

### In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:

  * We will notify the users via email within 7 business days.

  * We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

### Disclosure

The owner of this blog is sometimes compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though I may receive compensation for my posts or advertisements, I always give my honest opinion, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely my own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

Due to the nature of my work, I often receive products to test or review. I am occasionally a guest of tourism destinations, hotels, and/or restaurants. I do not endorse activities, companies, or brands that I would not spend my own money on.

I do occasionally post affiliate links. If you click those links and make a purchase, it does not cost you extra but I do I earn a small commission if you purchase the product through those links. I do not post things I have not personally used myself. These links help fund the cost of running this website.

### To be in accordance with CANSPAM and GDPR we agree to the following:

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at **christyandscott {AT} ordinarytraveler {DOT} com**  and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

You have the right to be forgotten on the sites you visit.

You can unsubscribe or unfollow at any time, for any reason. You can remove cookies by clearing your browser history at any time.

We do not use your names/emails or data associated with any specific individual outside of their designated 3rd party services as noted above.

If you would like us to remove any further data, please email us and we’ll be happy to discuss our data policies further and see if we have any further data that can be removed.

But please note that by emailing us to discuss this, you have to tell us more data about yourself than we typically have access to in the first place.

### Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us by emailing  **christyandscott {AT} ordinarytraveler {DOT} com**
